我只是想表明我不在乎这个男人
I'm simply making the point that I do not care for the man.
我明白那点 但是
I'm well aware of that, but
也许你对他的评价有误
perhaps you've misjudged him.
我向你保证 他就是个道德卫士
I assure you he is every bit the prig I have described.
■
本字幕由
ShinY深影字幕组
原创译制
深影字幕组论坛
http://shinybbs.vip
我们都有权发表意见
We're all entitled to our opinions.
如果你坚持要跟波茨先生调情的话
If you insist on this dalliance with Mr. Potts
至少你能说服他让他允许我进入停尸房
the least you can do is convince him to allow me access to the mortuary.
第一 我们只是朋友
Firstly, we are merely friends.
第二 如果我们的关系更进一步 虽然我们没有
Secondly, if we were more than that which we are not
我不可能让巴拿巴改变他的规则
I couldn't possibly ask Barnabas to change his rules.
■
|
巴拿巴
Barnabas?
我有东西要买
I've shopping to do.
但市场在这边
But the market's that way.
我要去汉威尔街的佩特福
I'm going to c in Hanwell Street.
买新帽子吗
Buying a new hat?
让我猜猜
Ah, let me guess.
这事肯定跟巴拿巴有关
This is something to do with a certain Barnabas.
我没时间跟你扯这些
I don't have time for this.
- 你今天要去见他吗 - 再见 利兹
- Are you seeing him today? - Goodbye, Lizzie.
纳什父子私家侦探事务所
P·纳什先生
老板
什么事
Yes, what is it?
我有那位女侦探的消息 先生
I have that information on the lady detective, sir.
PEG
435-P72
伊莱莎·H·斯嘉丽
编号 357/16/82
进来
Come!
翻译  黑猫
翻译  车厘子团子
翻译  西倜
翻译  Tammy
翻译  凌大
校对&后期  飒白恬
斯嘉丽小姐和公爵
第二季 第四集
福林特博士牌
万能圣水
大病小病 药到病除
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet!
我是道尔 福林特博士的助手
Mr. Doyle. Assistant to Dr. Flint.
我的雇主希望您能让我们见上一面
My employer had hoped that you might grant us a meeting.
福林特博士想雇佣您
Dr. Flint would like to hire you
处理一件相当敏感的问题
on a rather sensitive issue.
但你能胜任这份工作吗 小姑娘
But are you up to the job, young lady?
我向您保证 许多客户对我的工作十分满意
I can assure you I have had many satisfied clients.
看看你
By the looks of you,
一阵风就能将你吹走
one puff of wind would see you blow over.
我们收到了这封匿名信
We received this anonymous letter.
信里称 给我们的一瓶圣水下了毒
It advised that a bottle of our elixir had been poisoned
搁在我们一个市场摊位的架子上
and placed on the shelf of one of our market stalls.
我们对它进行了测试 结果
We had it tested and indeed
它确实含有一种毒素
it does contain a toxin
提取自一种被称为"地狱天使"的植物
it does contain a toxin derived from a plant known as the 'angel of inferno'.
福林特博士牌
万能圣水
大病小病 药到病除
"将一千英镑留在圣潘克拉斯车站
£1000 to be left at St. Pancras Station.
如果不交钱 勒索金会提高
If it's not forthcoming the money demanded will increase
并且会有第二次下毒事件"
and a second poisoning will occur.
这是几天前写的
This is dated several days ago
截止日期都已经过了
and the deadline has passed.
你们为什么不早点雇佣我
Why didn't you engage me sooner?
我们不希望大众获悉此事
We wished to keep it from public knowledge.
因此 您必须签署保密协议
As such, you will have to sign a confidentiality agreement.
好吧 我得先看一遍
Well, I'll have to read it thoroughly first.
你到底接不接这个案子 小姑娘
Will you work this case or not, young lady?
我的名字是斯嘉丽小姐
My name is Miss Scarlet.
如果我成了你的客户
If I'm to be your client
我愿意怎么喊你就怎么喊你
I shall call you whatever I damn well please!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我此刻正忙于其他事情
I'm extremely busy with other things at the moment,
所以关于你们的...
so in regards to your...
拜托
Please...
我当然会找时间接下它
I'll of course find time to take it.
我签在哪
Where do I sign?
♪我是摩登少将的典范♪
I am the very model of a modern Major-General,
档案室
♪我懂得植物学 动物学和矿物学♪
I've information vegetable, animal, and mineral,
菲茨罗伊唱的是《少将之歌》
出自1879年的喜歌剧《潘赞斯的海盗》
♪我知道英格兰诸王 还能援引历史上的大战♪
I know the kings of England, and I quote the fights historical
♪从马拉松到滑铁卢 按顺序排列♪
From Marathon to Waterloo, in order categorical
♪我非常擅长积分和微积分计算♪
I'm very good at integral and differential calculus
♪也知道微生物的学名♪
I know the scientific names of beings animalculous
♪简而言之 论及植物学 动物学和矿物学♪
In short, in matters vegetable, animal, and mineral
♪我是现代少...♪
I am the very model of a modern Major...
您好 父亲
Hello, father.
我以为你已经让我失望透顶了
I though it impossible that you could disappoint me any further
但很明显 我错了
but clearly I was wrong.
我唯一庆幸的是 你母亲不用亲眼看见这一切
I'm only glad your mother isn't alive to see this.
你应当成为一名警探的
You're supposed to be a police detective!
现在却在做档案管理员
You're a filing clerk!
我是怎么教你的
What have I taught you?
- 威灵顿督察在哪 - 我在这 长官
- Where is Inspector Wellington? - I am here, Sir.
你应该教会我的儿子如何成为一名警探
You were meant to teach my son to be a detective.
但他却像个初级员工一样在这整理档案
Now I find him filing here like some junior clerk!
我可以解释 长官
I can explain, Sir.
您的儿子是一名极其娴熟的警官
Your son is an extremely proficient police officer
然而 他入职仅仅半年
However, he has been in the force for barely half a year
成为警探意味着他有更多的东西要学
and entering at detective level means he still has a great deal to learn.
是我的儿子要求的这个职位吗
Did my son request this position?
不是 长官
No, Sir.
是我决定让他担任行政职务
I took the decision to put him on administration duties
因为我觉得他必须从头开始
since I felt it imperative that he acquire the knowledge
学习知识
from the ground up.
听好了 威灵顿督察
Well, listen carefully, Inspector Wellington
因为我要告诉你事情究竟该如何进展
because I am going to tell you exactly what is going to happen here.
菲茨罗伊从即刻起恢复警探身份
Fitzroy will be reinstated as a police detective with immediate effect.
从出生起就一直折磨着他的那个软弱性格
The.. uh.. feeble insubstantial character that has blighted him since birth
将从他的身上抹去
will be knocked out of him
他会变成一个让他的家族最终引以为傲的男人
and he will be turned into a man that his family can finally be proud of.
这是总监的原话 长官 不是我的
The Police Commissioner's words, Sir. Not mine.
他坚持要菲茨罗伊在年底当上督察
He's insisting that Fitzroy make inspector by the end of the year.
总监怎么说 你就怎么做
The Police Commissioner gets what the Police Commissioner wants.
但我是认真的 长官
But I'm serious, Sir.
我的工作是确保警察厅的有效运作
My job is to ensure the effective running of this constabulary.
我的一半时间都在做财政计划
Half my time is.. Financial planning!
在过去的几个月里 我一直在请求总监
For the last few months I've been petitioning the Commissioner
要求内政部审查我们的预算
to push the Home Office to review our budgets.
仅在托特纳姆一地
This city has grown with
就增加了八英里的新住宅街道
8 extra miles of new residential streets
需要巡逻
to patrol in Tottenham alone.
但照顾他的儿子完全是另外一回事 长官
Surely, favouring his son is an entirely separate matter, Sir.
如果你这么认为的话 那你要学的还有很多
You've a lot to learn if you think that is the case.
您看 菲茨罗伊这个年轻人非常不错
Look, Fitzroy is a thoroughly decent young man
但他不是当警探的料 更别提当督察了
but he's no detective, let alone inspector material.
街道正在变得越来越暴力
The streets are getting more violent year on year
如果他重新参与行动
and if he's placed back in action
他将不仅是拿自己的生命冒险
he will not only put his own life at risk
还有我手下的人
but my men, too.
坐
Take a seat.
你和我最近意见不合
You and I have been at odds recently.
但是
However,
关于此事 你所说的我都认同
in this instance, there is nothing you have said that I do not concur with.
但是 尽管如此
But, be that as it may...
在这件事上 我们恐怕都没得选
I'm afraid we have no choice in the matter
- 所以我已经做了决定 - 长官
- Which is why I've made a decision. - Sir?
菲茨罗伊将从你麾下
Fitzroy will be taken from your command
转去菲尔普斯警探那里
and placed under detective Phelps.
菲尔普斯憎恶这孩子 长官
Phelps hates the lad, Sir.
如果是这样的话
Well, if that's the case
他要么放弃 要么殉职
he can give up or die trying.
如果殉职 他的家族一定会收到一枚勋章
And if that happens I'm sure his family will receive a medal
他父亲一定会喜欢的
which I'm sure will go down well with his father.
听我说 小伙子
Listen to me, laddie...
你的前途一片光明
You've got a good future ahead of you.
菲茨罗伊只会败坏你的名声
Fitzroy will only blacken your reputation.
这是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
当然不是 长官
Of course not, Sir.
好极了
Good.
他会被转到菲尔普斯警探手下
Then he will transfer to detective Phelps
即刻生效
with immediate effect.
这是命令
And that is an order.
是 长官
Yes, Sir.
下午好 波茨先生
Good afternoon, Mr.Potts.
市停尸房
禁止公众进入
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet.
我需要您的建议
I was in need of your advice.
我有个问题
I've a question about
是关于一种特定植物的毒性
the poisonous properties of a particular plant.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet,
我的休息时间结束 必须回岗位了
my break is over and I must return to my duties.
我不能在街上磨蹭
I cannot loiter here on the street
和你讨论植物学
discussing botany with you.
我十分理解 波茨先生
I quite understand, Mr. Potts,
市停尸房
所以我或许应该进去问
so perhaps I should come inside.
大英图书馆离这个地方
The British Library is a mere
只有十分钟的步行路程
ten minutes stroll from this very spot.
我相信你会在这个神圣的殿堂
I'm sure you'll find the answers to all manner of questions
找到各种问题的答案
within its hallowed walls.
失陪了
If you'll excuse me...
艾薇早上问起过您
Ivy was asking after you this morning.
- 她有吗 - 是的
- Was she? - Yes.
我当然把您描述得很讨喜
I, of course, gave a very agreeable account of you
并且我很乐意接着这么做
and will happily continue to do so.
你在说什么
What are you saying, exactly?
字面意思是"你帮我抓背 我也帮你抓"
你帮我 我也帮你
You scratch my back... And I'll scratch yours.
女士不应该说这种不得体的话
A Lady should not say such unseemly things.
有违基督教教义
It is not Christian...
你帮助我 我就会继续替你说好话
You help me and I will continue to sing your praises.
这...
That...
- 这是敲诈 - 这是生意
- That is blackmail! - That is business...
所以 成交吗
So, do we have a deal?
那儿有个男人
There's a man...
他好像在监视你
He seems to be watching you.
我会回来的 波茨先生
I'll be back, Mr. Potts.
省省吧
Save us!
进来
Come.
上帝啊
Dear God...
我猜这是你父亲的手笔
This is your father's handiwork, I assume.
长官
Sir!
我想表达我多么期待出外勤
I'd like to convey how much I'm looking forward to coming back to the field.
但是
But..
我觉得这其中有些误会
I think there's been some mistake.
我被告知去菲尔普斯警探那里报告
I've been told to report to detective Phelps.
没有误会
There's no mistake.
但是菲尔普斯警探讨厌我
But.. Detective Phelps loathes me.
他觉得我就是一个含着银汤匙出生
He thinks I'm just some spoiled toff
被宠坏了的花花公子
born with a silver spoon in my mouth.
菲尔普斯警探是一个非常好的警官
Detective Phelps... is a very good officer.
他是个恶棍
He's a thug!
菲尔普斯警探是你的上级
Detective Phelps is your superior
你要尊重他 明白了吗
and you will show respect. Is that understood?
是 长官
Yes, Sir.
没事的话就退下吧
Now, if there's nothing else...
我只是...
I just...
我不理解为什么我不能当您的部下
I don't understand why I can't stay under your command.
你是在暗示我要让你过得轻松点吗
Are you somehow suggesting that I'd give you an easier time of it?
- 当然不是 长官 - 那好
- Of course not, Sir. - Good.
现在立刻回去工作
Now get back to work.
是 长官
Yes, Sir.
纳什父子
私家侦探事务所
你为什么要跟踪我
Why are you following me?
非常荣幸得以见到大名鼎鼎的女侦探
How I've longed to meet the lady detective.
我叫帕特里克·纳什 是这里的老板
It's Patrick Nash, proprietor.
那我得问你了
Then I'll ask you, instead.
你为什么要跟踪我
Why are you following me?
斯嘉丽小姐 当我第一次听闻您的大名时
When I first heard about you, Miss Scarlet,
我还以为当侦探
I assumed being a detective
仅仅是您的爱好而已
was a mere hobby.
可能就是帮有钱的老女人找找她们的狗
You might find the odd rich lady's missing poodle,
但很快就会厌倦的
but you'd soon tire of it.
事实上 我手下的人听说有位女侦探 都乐了
In fact, my men were so amused by the idea of a female detective.
纷纷打赌您能坚持多久
They took bets on how long you'd last.
但几周时间过去了
But weeks went by
然后几个月也过去了
then months
您仍然坚持着这份职业
and you're still in the game
不知怎的 大家谈起您时都没那么好笑了
and somehow you became... Less amusing.
你想干什么
What do you want?
您意志坚定 胸怀大志 又求知若渴
You are determined, ambitious, hungry...
三种品质体现得淋漓尽致
The holy trinity.
简单来说 我希望您能来为我工作
In short, I want you to come and work for me.
不如移步到我的办公室 我们详谈
Shall we step into my office? Talk terms?
我听说过您的事务所 纳什先生
I've heard of your agency, Mr Nash.
以及您和您的手下调查案件的方式
And the means by which you and your men investigate.
我听说敲诈勒索是你们最喜欢的工具
I hear blackmail is your favourite tool.
您亲自见识见识 总比听信谣言的好
Surely, you know better than to listen to rumours.
多谢您的邀请 但我拒绝
Thank you for your offer, but no, thank you.
还请管好你的狗
But please call off your dogs.
太可惜了 毕竟我们如此兴趣相投
It's a shame, since we are kindred spirits.
作为爱尔兰人 我明白面临偏见的感受
As an Irishman, I know what it is to face prejudice.
我可以保证 我们根本不是一类人
I can assure you we have nothing in common.
严格来说并不是这样
That's not strictly true.
你接了福林特的案子吧
You took Flint's case, right?
他那天那么晚才去找你查案
There is a reason why you were brought on to this case
是有原因的
so late in the day.
福林特先来找的我
Dr Flint came to see me first,
但是我的收费太高了
but I was too expensive, of course.
然后他去了迪伦父子那里
So he went to see Dillon & Son.
他们的收费对这位老守财奴来说同样太高了
They were also too costly for the old miser.
于是他走遍了整座城市
So he went around the city...
但都徒劳无功
To no avail...
直到他找到了全伦敦收费最低的那个人
Until he found someone with the lowest fees in London.
就是你
You.
你这样收费太掉价了
You're selling yourself short.
我怎么收费不关你的事
What I charge is no business of yours.
我要和你竞价的时候就关我的事了
It is when I have to undercut you.
我会派我的手下去告诉福林特
I'll be sending one of my men to let Dr Flint know
我改变主意了
I've changed my mind.
我将免费提供服务
He can have my services... For free.
当然 除非你重新考虑一下我的工作邀请
Unless of course, you wish to reconsider my offer.
纳什父子
私家侦探事务所
既然这样
Well, in that case...
那我们公平竞争
May the best man win.
我很期待 斯嘉丽小姐
I look forward to it, Miss Scarlet.
我很喜欢挑战
I do love a challenge.
皇家植物学会
The Royal Botanical Society is
一向非常欢迎新成员的加入 贝尔弗里小姐
always happy to welcome new members, Miss Belfry.
太好了 汉弗莱斯先生
That is music to my ears, Mr Humphries.
我只是位业余爱好者罢了
I'm only an amateur enthusiast,
但是我想这样能够更亲近自然
but I think I can be close to nature.
天哪
Oh, my!
多可爱的灌木啊
Oh, my. What a lovely shrub!
那不是灌木 贝尔弗里小姐
That is no shrub, Miss Belfry...
那属于蕨类
That is a fern.
准确来说 是欧紫萁
Osmunda Regalis to be precise.
真感谢您纠正我 汉弗莱斯先生
How I do love to be corrected, Mr Humphries.
事实上
In fact...
关于另一种植物
Perhaps you might give me
我想听听您的专业意见
your expert advice on another plant.
叫做"地狱天使"
The 'angel of inferno'.
它的毒性特质和异域风情
Its poisonous properties and exotic location
让我遐想无限
have quite captured my imagination.
正如您也激发了我的遐想 亲爱的
As you have captured mine, my dear.
如果我有说错的地方还请您指正
And please, correct me if I'm wrong...
我似乎从书上看到 这种植物
Did I read that it not only grows
位于北美洲大陆南部的一个国家
不仅生长在危地马拉的火山坡上
on the volcanic slopes of Guatemala
在这个植物学会里也有种植 是吗
but also here, at the Society?
确实 我们这里是有这种植物
Indeed, we do have the plant.
但是 鉴于它的毒性
However, due to its toxic capabilities,
它被存放在一个仅限会员进入的区域
it is kept in a section for members only
但您目前
and at present
还不是正式会员
you are not a member.
我可以把您的名字加到等候名单上
I could add your name to our waiting list.
一张非常长的等候名单
Our very long waiting list...
又或者 作为馆长
Or perhaps, as curator,
我可以把您的名字移到最上面
I may be able to move your name to the top.
那太好了 汉弗莱斯先生
That's so kind, Mr Humphries.
不过能否让我先看一眼你们的会员名单
But might I have a little peep at your membership list first?
作为一位未婚女士
As an unmarried lady,
和正确的人交往非常必要
it's imperative I associate with only the right sort.
当然 我办公室里有名单
Of course. I have the list in my office.
但是我快赶不上下一个预约会面了
However, I am overdue for my next appointment,
或许
so perhaps you could...
您可以明天再来吗
Come back tomorrow?
我太喜欢玫瑰了
How I do love roses.
我的天哪
Oh, my goodness!
我的手指好像划破了
I seem to have pricked my finger.
亲爱的贝尔弗里小姐
Oh, my dear Miss Belfry...
我感觉有些头晕 汉弗莱斯先生
I'm feeling a little faint, Mr Humphries.
我可以借用您的办公室处理一下伤口吗
Might I attend to my injury in the privacy of your office?
我的预约可以延后
My appointment can wait.
我一个人就好
Alone...
我不需要您的帮助 汉弗莱斯先生
I do not need your help, Mr Humphries.
此刻我也无法给您提供帮助 贝尔弗里小姐
Nor would I be free to give it to you at this precise moment, Miss Belfry.
你看
You see,
有警官到访说有紧急事务需要我配合
the police are here and require my assistance on an urgent matter.
会员名单 汉弗莱斯先生
Membership list, Mr Humphries..
没问题 贝茨督察
Of course, Inspector Bates.
您说您是贝茨督察
Inspector Bates, you say...
我和伦敦警察厅的警官们很熟
I'm well acquainted with the officers at Scotland Yard
但我之前从未听说过您
but I've not heard mention of you before.
您与伦敦警察厅的人很熟悉是吗
You're well acquainted with Scotland Yard?
怎么个熟法 女士
In what capacity, madam?
我看您不像是会违法的人
You don't look like a law-breaker to me.
您是怎么认识警察厅的人的呢 贝尔弗里小姐
How exactly are you acquainted, Miss Belfry?
我的叔叔在内政部工作
My uncle works for the Home Office.
那我们可能见过
Well, we may have met.
请问您叔叔贵姓
What's his name?
他姓... 芬彻奇
Mr Fenchurch.
啊 是了 芬彻奇先生
Ay, yes. Mr Fenchurch.
我和他见过几次
Met him on a number of occasions.
一个人的名声败坏至此真是耻辱啊
It's such a shame that one's reputation can be lost forever.
我敢说他的大多数同事
I'd wager many of his colleagues
肯定都经常光顾东区的那家妓院吧
have frequented that particular east end brothel.
他被抓捕真是太不幸了
It's unfortunate that he was caught.
我无意冒犯 汉弗莱斯先生
I don't wish to be rude, Mr Humphries...
但这涉及机密
But this is a confidential matter.
当然 督察
Absolutely, Inspector.
如果您不介意的话 贝尔弗里小姐
If you don't mind, Miss Belfry.
我希望你这一天过得比我好些
I hope you've had a better day than I have.
我不信
I doubt it.
都是因为这个人既然你问了
The cause, since you ask..
我可没问
I didn't.
就是这个人
Him.
纳什父子... 他有儿子吗
Nash and Sons - if the man has any sons.
他就是个骗子
He's a liar and a crook.
他的调查方式非常值得争议
His means of investigation are debatable
但那不是警察厅关心的问题
but that's not the Met's problem.
警察们请他探案 收到结果
The police use him. Gets results.
也不多过问
No questions asked.
他要跟我价格竞争 截胡一个客户
Well, he's undercutting me with a client..
一个本身就很讨厌的客户
A client who is himself a very unpleasant man.
所以如果你是来寻求慰藉和放松的 威廉
So if you're here for some pleasant company, William
那你来错地方了
you've come to the wrong place.
我今天过得很糟糕
I've had a horrible day.
跟我打交道的每一个人都很讨厌
Every man I've had to deal with has been detestable.
幸好我顺路来拜访了一下
Well, I'm glad I dropped by.
我也很高兴你来了
I'm glad you did, too.
事实就是 纳什掌握的资源是我的十倍
The fact is this Nash has ten times my resources
我需要你的帮助 威廉
and I need your help, William.
伊莱莎 我的世界不是围着你转的
Eliza, my world doesn't revolve around you.
我也有自己的事要解决
I Have my own problems.
我正在追查那个勒索犯
I'm trying to hunt down a blackmailer
要是抓不到他 会有另一瓶药被下毒
and if I don't another bottle of this will be poisoned.
更严重的是 纳什会赢得这个案子
And even worse, Nash will win the case.
让纳什赢下案子比公众身亡更严重吗
Nash winning a case is worse than a member of the public dying?
- 别曲解我的意思 - 我没有
- Don't twist my words. - I didn't.
伊莱莎 这事很严重 你通知警察厅了没有
Eliza, this is serious. Have the police been informed?
没
No.
这是高度机密的
It's highly confidential.
一旦有生命威胁就不是了
Not when there's a threat to life it isn't.
但我已经签了保密协议
But I've signed a confidentiality agreement.
你觉得我想要或是需要更多案件吗
Do you think that I want or need more cases?
但是作为执法者
But as an officer of the law...
当公众生命安全受威胁时
When there is a danger to the general public,
警察必须调查
then the police must investigate.
好吧
Fine.
我需要一些时间来写笔记
I need time to write up my notes.
下班前我会把我掌握的内容都给你
I'll bring you what I have by the end of the day.
我知道你这个表情
I know that look...
什么表情
What look?
就是你此刻在脑海中进行大量算计
The look that is covering a multitude of calculations
而你试图掩盖时的表情
that are currently racing through your head.
我不懂你在说什么 威廉
I've no idea what you are talking about, William.
你当然不懂
Of course you don't.
记得今天结束之前给我
End of the day, Eliza..
你今晚应该在家里好好吃一顿晚餐
You should have a proper hot dinner at home this evening.
而不是像这样在办公桌上吃 这是不对的
Eating supper at your desk - it's not right.
我不知道你父亲会怎么说
I don't know what your father'd say...
不对 我知道他会怎么说
Actually, I do know what your father'd say..
"别管了 艾薇
'Don't bother, Ivy,
反正她也不会听的"
she doesn't listen anyway'.
你到底在找什么
What exactly are you looking for?
不管下毒人是谁...
Whoever this poisoner is...
他们有权进入植物学会
They had access to the Botanical Society.
那是除危地马拉外
The only place other than Guatamala
唯一种植这种"地狱天使"的地方
that grows this 'angel of inferno'.
我试图确定这个学会成员是谁 但...
I tried to establish who the member is, but...
到现在 我只找到几个
As yet, I've only found a few
他们还都和福林特博士毫无关联
and of those I can find absolutely no connection with Dr. Flint.
你现在应该去苏格兰场了吧
Shouldn't you be on your way to Scotland Yard, by now?
我以为你会去跟威灵顿督察
I thought you had to share your findings
- 说你的发现 - 我会的
- with Inspector Wellington. - And I will.
但今天还有时间
But I have until the end of the day.
我一定要先找到点线索
I'm determined to find some leads first.
如果苏格兰场破了案子 我也要沾点光
If Scotland Yard crack this case, I want to get some credit.
其次 我不想输给纳什
Moreover, I definitely don't want Nash to win.
能找摩西帮忙吗
Can't you get Moses to help you?
要是知道他在哪 我就找了
I would if I knew where he was.
他去干什么了
Where does he disappear to?
最好别问
Better not to ask.
我去拜访了波茨先生
I saw Mr Potts earlier.
他说喜欢你的新帽子
He said he liked your new hat.
是吗
Did he?
所以你今天确实见他了吗
So you did see him today?
我爱死这东西了
I love this stuff.
用了好多年
Used it for years.
它真的什么都能治
It really is a cure for everything.
咳嗽 感冒
Coughs and colds
还"比任何肥皂更能去除顽固污渍"
and 'better at getting out stubborn stains than any soap can'.
我保证 福林特博士不是医学博士
I can assure you, Dr Flint is no doctor.
这所谓仙药也只是调味水
Nor is this elixir anything other than flavoured water.
都是骗人的
It's all a con.
不好意思
Excuse me,
我记得某人小时候还甘之如饴
but I remember a certain young lady used to love it as a girl.
但当时它名字不一样
But then it had a different name...
叫"福林特&道尔牌魔药"
'Flint and Doyle's Magic Medicine'.
事实上 有时候我觉得你为了吃上一勺
In fact, sometimes I think you had a sore throat
故意说自己喉咙痛
just so I would give you a spoonful.
你刚说"福林特&道尔"吗
Did you just say 'Flint and Doyle'?
福林特博士牌万能圣水
吸气...
Breathe in...
呼气
And breathe out.
我讨厌那声音
I don't like the sound of that at all.
你胸腔有个破口 塞德里克
There is a crackle on your chest, Cedric.
我跟你说过 出门不能...
What have I told you about going out without a..
我跟他说了很多遍了 斯坦霍普医生
I've told him many times, Doctor Stanhope
他应该买辆新马车
that he should get a new carriage.
你们两个别大惊小怪了 我又不是小孩
Would you two stop fussing over me like I was a child.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet?
抱歉 原谅我突然过来
Please, forgive the unexpected visit
但我想和道尔先生单独说几句
but I was hoping to have a private word with Mr Doyle.
你想对道尔说的 都能和我说
Whatever you have to say to Mr Doyle, you can say it to me.
你不愿告知你的发现
Your unwillingness to share your findings
说明你的调查没有进展
suggests you have made no inroads.
无所谓
No matter,
反正现在我又请了个机构干活
since now I have an additional agency working for me.
是的 我知道 是纳什父子
Yes, I'm aware of that. Nash and Sons.
虽然他并没有儿子
Not that he has any sons...
他们相信明天这个时候前
They are confident that they will have the blackmailer in custody
就能抓到勒索犯
by this time tomorrow.
请来吧 塞德里克
Come along now, please, Cedric.
我要回诊所
I have to return to my practice
能顺路送你回家
and I can drop you at home on the way.
你想和我聊吗 请坐
You wished to speak to me? Please.
你们制出的药品
The remedy you manufacture...
曾经有个不太一样的名字
At one time it had a slightly different name...
叫"福林特&道尔牌魔药"
'Flint and Doyle's Magic Medicine'?
福林特博士去印度时认识了我父亲
My father met Dr Flint when he went to India,
当时他在寻找一种健康药品的成分
looking for ingredients for a health remedy.
他们成了搭档 我父亲搬来这里
They became partners and my father moved over here.
没人会买"福林特&马哈金"这种名字有印度味的产品
Nobody would have bought a product called 'Flint and Mahajinn', so...
所以我父亲改姓道尔
My father changed his name to Doyle.
我太懂这种困境了
I know all too well that dilemma.
我办公室外挂的仍然是我父亲的名字
It's still my father's name that hangs outside my office.
他们一起建起了事业
They built the business together
而我父亲去世后...
and then when my father died...
福林特博士就把他名字从产品上摘掉了
Dr Flint took his name off the product.
这种行为肯定会招来报复吧
Surely, such an action would have caused some resentment?
福林特博士是个好老板
Dr Flint has been a good employer to me
如果你怀疑我 你就搞错了
and if I am under suspicion, then you're mistaken.
我必须考虑所有可能性 道尔先生
I have to consider all possibilities, Mr Doyle.
如果没其他事 我要工作了
If you will excuse me, I have work to do.
请便
As you wish.
福林特博士 制药公司
皇家植物学会
十分抱歉
I do apologise.
我的钱包 她偷了我的钱包
My purse! She's stolen my purse.
小偷
Thief!
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
她偷了我的钱包
She's taken my purse!
我没做过
I've done no such thing.
我看到她拿了放进自己口袋
I saw her take it and put it in her pocket.
别闹了
Don't be ridiculous.
看啊 她拿了 你们看
There! She has it, you see.
- 不是我 - 请跟我走 女士
- No! - Come along with me, madame.
不是我拿的
It wasn't me who took it.
威灵顿督察
Inspector Wellington.
真高兴见到您
How nice to see you.
你好 艾薇 我找伊莱莎
Hello, Ivy. I'm looking for Eliza.
她不在办公室
She's not at her office.
恐怕她也不在这里
Ah, well she's not here either, I'm afraid.
想留句话吗
Would you like to leave a message?
她本来应该给我送点情报
She was meant to deliver some information to me
但她好像忘了
but it seems to have slipped her mind.
介意我进来等吗
Do you mind if I come in and wait?
我正要吃晚饭
I was just about to have dinner.
这样啊
Oh, well.
那最好了
That'll be most welcome.
她根本没想
She never had any intention
给我送那个文件 完全没有
of bringing me that file... none whatsoever.
她除了自己的利益 什么都不会考虑
She's no thought for anything other than her own gain.
这么说不好吧 威灵顿督察
Well, that's a little unfair, Inspector Wellington.
伊莱莎是有不对
Yes, Eliza has her faults
但她只是努力走出自己的路
but she's just trying to make her way in life.
再来点豆子吗 波茨先生
More beans, Mr Potts?
谢谢 伍兹小姐
Thank you, Miss Woods.
督察来点吗
Inspector?
谢谢你
Thank you.
你应该赞同我吧 波茨先生
You should agree with me Mr Potts.
她让你很头疼
She's caused you many a headache.
你总说她有多不可理喻
You always say how impossible she can be.
那些不是我原话
Those were not words of mine, exact words.
不 你原话是 "不可理喻 不可信任 心无虔诚"
No, your exact words were 'impossible, untrustworthy and unchristian'.
斯嘉丽小姐有时头脑简单
Miss Scarlet can be somewhat single-minded
但我想伍兹小姐说的也有道理
but I think what Miss Woods is saying does also have some truth.
斯嘉丽小姐是个努力在男人掌控的世界里
Miss Scarlet is a woman trying to run a business
打拼事业的女性
in a world usually the preserve of a man.
来吧 承认吧
Come on, admit it...
你厌恶她
You loathe her.
我从没流露过像"厌恶"这种强烈的情感
I've never suggested anything so strongly as 'loathe'.
如果有 也是强烈钦佩她的毅力
If anything, I admire her fortitude.
你态度变了
You've changed your tune.
我记得你说...
I remember you saying...
伍兹小姐 晚饭真的很美味
Miss Woods, this really is a delicious dinner.
豆子爽脆又新鲜
The beans are crisp and fresh
饺子馅多又湿润
and the dumplings so plump and moist.
为绅士做饭是我的荣幸
It's a pleasure to cook for a gentleman.
等我找到她 她最好给我好好解释
She'd better have a damn good explanation when I catch up with her.
我能走了吗
Am I free to go?
我不知道你整晚在这里
I had no idea you were down here all night.
不然就来陪你了
I could have kept you company.
在感谢威灵顿督察保释我的时候
I'll be sure to mention that to Inspector Wellington
我肯定会跟他说的
when I thank him for bailing me.
保释你的不是他
It wasn't him that bailed you.
我亲爱的斯嘉丽小姐
My dear Miss Scarlet.
再次与您相聚真令人愉快
What a pleasure it is to be once again in your convivial company.
彼此彼此 辛克莱尔先生
Likewise, Mr Sinclair.
是你保释我的吗
Are you the reason for my bail?
确实是我
Indeed I am.
我还相信 这么一个好奇心强烈的女士
And I'm quite certain that a woman with such an enquiring mind
肯定会对巴兹尔·辛克莱尔为什么这么做
must have many questions as to why
充满疑问
Basil Sinclair would do such a thing.
但... 允许我解释 亲爱的
But... Allow me explain, my dear.
事实很简单
The simple fact is
只要你出现我的作品中
that whenever you have featured in my publication
它的销量就成倍提高
it has sold exponentially.
作为 《警务新闻画报》 的首席记者
And as chief correspondent of the Illustrated Police News
如果我不来探索
it would be remiss of me not to pursue
这位女侦探的进一步冒险 就太失职了
the further adventures of the Lady Detective.
你想写篇关于我的故事吗
You want to write a story about me?
我亲爱的斯嘉丽小姐
My dear Miss Scarlet,
如果你觉得最近的调查只是个小故事
if you wish to call your latest investigation a mere story,
那是你的特权
that is your prerogative.
我自己更喜欢用
I myself would rather
"敲诈 毒物与巫术的醉人组合"
'an intoxicating blend of blackmail, poison, and witchcraft'.
我的调查是高度机密
My investigation is highly confidential
但我保证里面没有什么巫术
but I can confirm that there's no witchcraft involved.
作为人民的管家 如果剥夺他们
As a steward of the people it would be cruel of me
阅读这座伟大城市故事的权利 就太残忍了
to deprive them of my tale of this great city of ours.
我说清楚了吗
Do I make myself quite clear?
没...
No...
不管你合作与否
I will write this article
我都会写这篇文章
with or without your co-operation
要么你做我的主角
and either you will be my heroine
要么纳什先生来做
or Mr. Nash will be my hero.
正如大家说的 选择权...
The choice, as they say...
在你
is yours.
这是敲诈
This is blackmail.
这是生意
This is business.
搞什么东西
Wot the 'ell?
马车在外面停着 我待会就来
Wagon's outside. I'll be out in a minute.
蠢货 要是你一分钟内捡不完
Strike a light. If this takes much longer
我就亲手办了你
I'll shoot you myself..
库珀那小子要逃跑了
That bloke Cooper will 'ave scarpered!
气死我了
That is right!
你们要突袭暴徒库珀吗
Are you doing a raid on the Cooper mob?
计划如此 要是这呆子手脚利索点的话
That's the plan - if this moron will 'urry up!
菲茨罗伊警探跟我行动
Detective Fitzroy is to come with me.
我这有个案子需要他帮忙
A case has just come up and I need his help.
上头说他...
The governor said that he..
我就是你的上司
I'm your governor
我说 菲茨罗伊跟我走
and I'm telling you Fitzroy is with me.
好的 公爵
Yes, Duke.
谢谢长官
Thank you, Sir.
别太在意他刚才说的话
He doesn't know what he's talking about.
跟我来
Come along.
相信您这次来访 是想要
I assume this visit is confirmation of your desire
皇家植物学会
成为我们的会员 贝尔弗里小姐
to become a member, Miss Belfry.
不过我有点担心您那个...
Although I am rather concerned regarding this...
在内政部工作的不检点的叔叔
wayward uncle of yours in the Home Office.
丑闻一出 我们就和他断了往来
Since the scandal my family have cut ties.
这样的话 我很荣幸为您介绍更多的细节
In that case, I would be honoured to brief you on every detail.
不过...
However...
您还记得吧 我曾说过
You might remember my mention of
有一份很长的等候名单 因此...
a rather long waiting list, so..
可否赏脸吃顿晚餐
Perhaps dinner...
届时细聊帮您安排到最前的事
To discuss moving your name to the top.
那太好了
Oh, that would have been delightful.
但是 我有点不舒服
However, I find myself somewhat under the weather.
昨天见到玫瑰过于兴奋
My over-enthusiasm for the roses yesterday...
划到的地方感染了
My little prick has become infected.
我亲爱的贝尔弗里小姐
My dear Miss Belfry...
流脓发臭了
Just some foul-smelling pus...
真倒霉
It's extremely frustrating
因为这伤 我昨晚缺席了你的演讲
because it also prevented me from attending your lecture last night.
其实是场新书发布会
It was more of a book launch.
伍尔维奇基金会为筹集资金
The Woolwich Trust was selling their
昨晚在售卖他们的新书
new publication to raise funds.
很有意义的项目
It's a very good cause.
为穷人提供医疗
Medicine for the poor.
新书里有一章是您感兴趣的"地狱天使"
The book has a chapter on your "angel of inferno".
肉眼可见 其叶子中分离的毒素会发光
Apparently, the toxin derived from the leaves has a luminous quality.
在夜光中闪耀的植物
The plant that glows in the dark..
好神奇
How extraordinary!
我能买一本吗
May I buy a copy of the book?
那天你在我办公室遇见的督察
Oh. That nice police inspector who you met in my office
他参加了发布会
He attended the launch.
买走了最后一本书
He bought the last copy.
他
Did he...
在会员名册里有什么发现吗
Find what he was looking for in your membership list?
不清楚
I've no idea.
显然 案件需要保密
Confidential case, apparently
但他有提起 离逮捕嫌疑人更近一步了
but he did say he was close to making an arrest.
书名是什么
This book.. What is it called?
这是昨晚新书发布会的宣传单
Here is a copy of the advertisement from last night's launch.
去大型书店就能找到这本书
You'll find the book in any good bookshop.
Woolwich Trust最新出版
《治愈与死亡——论植物的毒性》
所有盈利将用于"慈善基金"项目
"Kill or Cure - the Poisonous Properties of Plants".
那么 还有一件事
Now... To the other matter.
晚餐
Dinner.
我翻翻日记本
Let me just find my diary..
周一怎么样
Shall we say.. Monday,
您的伤口感染那时候该好了
which should give your infection time to heal.
好
Here we are..
那么...
So...
贝尔弗里小姐
Miss Belfry...
《治愈与死亡——论植物的毒性》
打住 你这样喘粗气...
Before you start, huffing and puffing..
首先 我现在需要深吸气一番 不会叹气
Firstly, I need a huff, not a puff.
第二 我不想再被骗一回
Secondly, I have no inclination to be lied to again
我现在就要那案子的档案
I want that case file, now.
我昨晚本想将情报交给你
And I would have given it to you last night
可是被纳什陷害 关入警局
had I not been arrested on some trumped-up charge made by Nash.
我在牢房待了一夜
I spent the night in the cells.
我知道 距离保释过去了几个小时
And yes, I have been released for hours
我本可以在这期间给你
and I could have brought it to you
但是我是专业侦探 威廉
but I'm a professional, William
我想再试试寻找线索突破口
and I wanted one last crack at finding a lead.
"我这个笨蛋在干嘛 她不是干得挺不错吗"
Idiot that I am, what's he doing? Hasn't she done a good job...
虽然你从没对我说过
Not that you'd ever actually say it to me.
我说了很多次
I've said that to you many times.
不够
Not nearly enough!
这里 这堆纸你都拿走
Here, have the damned papers.
反正也没头绪 正合你意
Another dead end anyway, which I'm sure will amuse you.
这就是你说的专业吗
This is you being professional, is it?
对不起 这几天太累了
I apologise. I've had a very trying few days.
但说真的
But I meant what I said.
我拖延着不交接案子
I delayed handing in the case
其实是想要得到你的认可
because I do want you to think well of my skills.
知道了
Fine.
来吧
Come on.
要去哪
Where am I going?
你得证明给我看 你只是因为这件事
At least give me credit to know that this little outburst
才突然发脾气
has one objective only.
表现得愧疚点 那我考虑
To induce guilt so that I would consent
让你和我一起查这个案子
to you working the case with me.
你说的毫无根据 颠倒主次 有悖事实
That is unfounded, unfair, absolutely not true.
别说了 带上档案
Just stop talking and bring the file
去年 福林特博士一直在找土地
For the last year Dr Flint has been looking for land
建新厂
to build an additional factory.
他在东区找到了一片便宜的荒地
He found some cheap waste land in the East End but
但那片地已被慈善项目征用
it had already been earmarked by a charity.
用来给穷人盖医院
They were going to build a hospital for the poor.
但福林特出价更高 买下了那块地
But Flint outbid them and bought the land instead.
准备得不错 警探
This is good work indeed, detective.
这个慈善机构不会就是伍尔维奇基金会吧
This charity wouldn't be called the Woolwich Trust, by any chance?
确实
The very one.
去做一份伍尔维奇基金会的会员名册
Get a list of members of this Woolwich Trust.
是 长官
Yes, Sir.
所以 道尔先生参加了
So, Mr Doyle attends a fund-raiser
伍尔维奇基金会的新书募捐活动
for the Woolwich Trust's book
那他肯定也支持基金会发起的
which means he must support their cause..
"穷人医疗项目"
"Medicine for the Poor".
而伍尔维奇基金会就是那家
And this same Woolwich Trust was the benevolent association
想要盖医院的慈善组织
that planned to build a hospital.
直至福林特抢走了土地
Until Flint stole the land.
道尔生活中也遭到福林特背叛
Mr Doyle was also personally betrayed by Flint
他父亲的名字从共同研发的药品中被除去
when his father's name was taken off their remedy.
他本该成为合伙人
He should have been a partner but...
但现在只是个没什么地位的助手
instead he's just a lowly assistant.
看来要找的人出现了
Sounds like we've got our man.
福林特博士
制药公司
道尔先生
Mr Doyle...
还有气... 刚干的
He's still breathing... just.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
有人给他下毒
He's been poisoned.
毫无疑问 下一个就是我
No doubt I shall be next!
我收到这个
I received this...
一封信
It's an envelope.
是打印出来的
It's in typeface.
敲诈者的信
It's from the blackmailer.
不用你说我也知道
I could have told you that.
里面写了什么
What does it say?
我还没打开
I haven't opened it
因为我才不在意他写了什么
because I do not care what it says.
这个人
Whoever is doing this
伤害了我唯一在意的人
has taken the only thing I care about.
我待他就像亲儿子一样
He is the closest thing I have to a son.
塞德里克 尼古拉斯还年轻 身体也好
Cedric, Nicolas is a strong young man.
他在这儿会得到最好的照顾
He will receive the best care here.
斯坦霍普医生
Dr Stanhope...
道尔先生真实情况如何
How is Mr Doyle? Really?
非常糟糕
Extremely poorly.
尼古拉斯·道尔是我见过最善良的人
There never was a kinder soul than Nicolas Doyle.
塞德里克是在害人害己
Cedric's a fool to himself.
你指的是敲诈一事吗
You speak of the blackmail?
你觉得 福林特博士该按对方要求给钱
You believe Dr Flint should pay the money demanded?
对 以结束这场闹剧
To stop this madness, yes.
两千英镑对他来说不算什么 不然下一个就该到他了
£2000 is nothing to him and my belief is he could be next.
斯坦霍普医生
Dr Stanhope...
失陪
Excuse me.
我要跟医生聊聊
I must confer with the doctors here.
菲茨罗伊给了张关于伍尔维奇基金会的会员名册
Fitzroy's made a list of all the members of the Woolwich Trust.
不需要看名册了 威廉
I don't need to see the list, William.
我知道谁是敲诈者
I know who the blackmailer is.
亨利·斯嘉丽私人侦探事务所
皇家植物学会的馆长
The curator at the Royal Botanical Society?
汉弗莱斯先生
Mr Humphries.
他能搞到"地狱天使"这种有毒植株
He had access to the poisonous plant, the angel of inferno.
其中提取的毒物是可发光的
And the poison is - luminous - you said.
对
Indeed.
那你说的第二名敲诈者是谁
And this second blackmailer that you mentioned?
信还没打开呢
But this is still sealed.
这能让你的故事更精彩 辛克莱尔先生
Oh, well, I thought it would enhance your story, Mr Sinclair.
这名侦探小姐 锁定了敲诈者的身份
A lady detective, so sure of the blackmailer
甚至连第二封信都不需要打开
she had no need to open the second letter.
不错 斯嘉丽小姐
Bravo, Miss Scarlet.
我觉得 你浪费了你的天赋
I do believe you have missed your calling.
编故事的时候你可是个天才
You are a natural when it comes to art of... spinning a story.
跟我不相上下
Almost as good as myself.
来自首席记者的高度赞许
High praise indeed, coming from the chief correspondent himself.
没错
Ah, yes...
跟我想的一样
Just as I thought.
你看 辛克莱尔先生
You see, Mr Sinclair.
这两处的字母X有明显的错误印迹
The letter X has a distinctive, faulty mark in both.
第一封勒索信里也有
Just like the first blackmail letter.
这表明 勒索信和宣传单出自同一部打字机
Which means they were all typed on the same typewriter.
馆长的打字机
The curator's typewriter..
一语中的
Precisely.
所以这个汉弗莱斯 既能拿到毒药
So this Humphries had access to both the poison
又能使用那台打字机敲出勒索信
and to the typewriter that wrote both of the blackmail letters
他还是伍尔维奇慈善基金的成员
and he was also a member of the Woolwich Trust.
基金会买了块便宜地
They had procured cheap land
要给穷人建医院
to build a hospital for the poor
但福林特博士出价更高
but Dr Flint outbid them.
他买地自用 打算建新药厂
He bought the land for himself to build a new factory, instead.
他被勒索就是对方的复仇
His extorsion was an act of revenge.
那就是说 没有巫术
No witchcraft, though..
不好意思 没有
No, I'm afraid not.
但是
Although..
毒药的迷幻质地
The luminous quality of the poison
也有一丝黑魔法的味道 对吧
has a touch of black magic, does it not?
确实
Indeed.
我要在一个小时后与威灵顿督察见面
I'm meeting Inspector Wellington in precisely one hour
地点在植物学会
at the Botanical Society,
汉弗莱斯先生将在那里被捕
when Mr Humphries will be arrested.
我猜您想一同前往
I assume you'd like to attend?
所以请看 福林特博士
So you see, Dr Flint,
我的证据明确指向汉弗莱斯先生
my evidence points quite firmly to Mr Humphries here.
我要让这恶棍关进铁窗
I want that scoundrel locked up!
我不是勒索者
I am no blackmailer.
斯嘉丽小姐
Ah, Miss Scarlet,
我正在向我的客户福林特博士解释
I was just explaining to my client, Dr Flint
我如何推断出汉弗莱斯先生就是罪魁祸首
how I deduced that Mr Humphries was the culprit.
你要把我们的联系方式放进新闻报道里 辛克莱尔
You make sure you put our contact detail on your piece, Sinclair.
我们怎么能错过宣传的好机会呢
Like we should pass up an opportunity for promotion.
你一直以来受雇于纳什先生
You were under the pay of Nash all along.
纳什先生是本报最慷慨的广告主之一
Mr Nash is one of our most generous advertisers.
有机会时 必须报答本报赞助商
We must repay our patrons where we can.
那共享我的证据也就是必需的了
And sharing my evidence was just the ticket.
我们永远感激你 斯嘉丽小姐
We're eternally grateful, Miss Scarlet.
我不保释你 你现在还在牢房里
Without my bail you'd still be in a police cell.
就是你害我被关进去的
You were the reason I was there in the first place!
你们为什么一直叫她斯嘉丽小姐
Why do you keep calling her 'Miss Scarlet'?
这是贝尔弗里小姐
This is Miss Belfry...
这位女士想要加入植物学会
The lady who wished to join the Society...
正如我不是警察 汉弗莱斯先生
Because just as I am no police inspector, Mr Humphries
这位也并非普通女士
this is no lady.
她是私家侦探
She is a private detective
令人惊叹 可不是吗
Impressive, is she not?
我也想留下多聊两句
Well, I'd love to stay and chat
不过我可能
but I'm afraid
必须得离开了
I really must get on.
把他抓去苏格兰场
Take him down to Scotland Yard.
请吧
Please...
求求了 这里面肯定有什么误会
please, there's been a terrible mistake..
福林特博士
Dr Flint!
我早就知道辛克莱尔先生在欺瞒我
I knew Mr Sinclair was double-crossing me.
所以我对他撒了谎 来误导纳什
That's why I lied to him to mislead Nash.
汉弗莱斯先生不是勒索者
Mr Humphries is not your blackmailer.
但是打字机的事儿...
But the typewriter...
首批打字机在X字母上都有同样的错误
That particular make the first edition has a common fault with its letter X.
如果汉弗莱斯不是勒索者
If Humphries is not the blackmailer..
谁才是
The who is?
爱德华 你怎么能如此对我
Edward, how could you do this to me?
我们本来要建一所医院
We were going to build a hospital.
让穷人终于能够被照料看护
A place where the poor could finally be nursed and looked after.
我们花费多年募资来买那块地
We'd spent years fund-raising to buy that piece of land.
一块终于能买得起的地
Somewhere we could finally afford.
然后你出现了 抢走了地
Then you come along... And take it from us
就因为价格低廉
because it was cheap.
你无耻
Shame on you!
你就是如此无耻 塞德里克
That you are, Cedric.
斯坦霍普博士意图勒索的钱
The money Dr Stanhope demanded
是要返还慈善基金
was to be funneled back into the charity.
补偿多年来已经支付的计划用地许可
It's recompense for what they'd paid out in planning permission
和建筑相关费用
and architects over the years.
这钱也为医院再次选址另开门路
It also gave ways of finding another site for the hospital.
你如何知道是他
How did you know it was him?
他知道加价后的勒索金额
He knew the increased amount the blackmailer was demanding
但他没看过勒索信
without having even seen the letter.
信件是密封的 直到在我办公室开封
It was sealed until I opened it in my office.
而且与我告诉辛克莱尔先生的不同
And contrary to what I told Mr Sinclair
汉弗莱斯先生不是伍尔维奇慈善基金的成员
Mr Humphries is not a member of the Woolwich Trust
斯坦霍普博士才是
but Dr Stanhope is.
他是基金会主席
He's their chairman.
他也是植物学会理事会的理事
He's also on the board of the Botanical Society
可以接近那棵有毒的植株
and he had access to the poisonous plant.
尼古拉斯中毒是怎么回事
About Nicolas..
斯坦霍普博士给他下了微量毒药
Dr Stanhope administered a mild dose of the poison.
意图使道尔先生昏迷不醒
His intention was to render Mr Doyle unconscious.
不是为了杀他
Not to kill him.
我在产品上恢复了你父亲的名字
I have reinstated your father's name on our product
你会成为我的商业伙伴
and you will be my partner.
他是对的
Yes, he's right.
我希望我们的公司能够买下那片地 捐出去
I want our company to buy that land and to donate it
这样给穷人的医院还是可以建
so the hospital for the poor can still be built.
我们应该以你父亲的名义捐献
We shall donate it in your father's name.
我的朋友 我亲爱的朋友
My friend. My dear, dear friend.
我以后再也不相信辛克莱尔这家伙了
I will never trust that toad Sinclair again.
你一开始居然愿意相信他
Why you trusted him in the first place
我也难以理解
is a mystery to me.
我听说你为了小菲茨罗伊做的事
I heard what you did for young Fitzroy,
把他撤出了对库珀黑帮的突击搜查
pulling him from that raid on the Cooper gang.
他对你可是大加赞誉
He cannot speak highly enough of you.
他们可不是普通黑帮
They're not just a gang.
他们是市内最为穷凶极恶的罪犯
They're among the most brutal criminals in the city.
他不去现场是万幸之事
He's very lucky not to have been out there.
请别对着我面露纵容的微笑
Please don't give me that indulgent smile.
这可不是纵容 这是恋慕
It's not indulgence, it's affection.
你说是就是
Of course it is.
威廉 别以为自己可以读懂我的心声
William... Do not presume to be able to read my mind.
如果我能读懂 那么我们就不必再聊天了
If I could then I'm quite sure that we would never speak again.
代我向波茨先生问好
To give my best to Mr Potts.
我不去太平间
I'm not going to the mortuary. I don't know.
在我看来 他会高频拜访你家的
From what I see, I believe he'll be a frequent visitor.
艾薇看起来被他迷住了
Ivy seems quite taken with him.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet..
菲茨罗伊警探
Detective Fitzroy.
你能将目光从斯嘉丽小姐身上移开吗
If you can drag your eyes from Miss Scarlet for a moment
刚刚出现了一个诈骗案 警探
a fraud case has just come in, detective.
是 长官
Yes, Sir.
蒙哥马利街上的珠宝商 伊登·布鲁姆
Jewellers on Montgomery Street. Eden Bloom.
去调查吧
Get me what you can find.
是 长官
Yes, Sir.
督察
Inspector...
我听说你把小菲茨罗伊
I hear you plucked young Fitzroy
从菲尔普斯警探那里拽出来协助你了
from Detective Phelps to assist you instead.
是的长官
Yes, Sir.
他有着百科全书般的毒药知识
He has encyclopaedic knowledge of poisons
对此案有帮助
I needed in this case.
你是说 百科全书般的
Encyclopaedic, you say?
令人印象深刻
Impressive.
去干活吧 警探
Well, get to it, detective.
是 长官
Yes, Sir.
你违反了另一个直接命令 督察
You disobeyed another direct order, Inspector.
我道歉 长官 但是我...
I apologise, Sir, but I...
小子
Laddie!
我在格拉斯哥街头长大 如你一样
I was born on the streets of Glasgow, just like you
我还和当年一样敏锐
and I'm as savvy as the day I was born.
别以为身居要职会改变我的本性
Do not assume my comfortable position here is turning me otherwise.
啊 您好 总监
Ah! Good day, Commissioner.
我桌上一瓶威士忌 饮者姓名可是您
I've a whisky with your name on it waiting on my desk.
那我希望是个大瓶
I hope it's a large one.
容量大 烈性强
Large and strong...
如同我对女人的口味一样
Just how I like my women.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet..
我想亲自祝贺您取得卓越的胜利
I wish to congratulate you in person on your magnificent win.
谢谢
Thank you.
能有机会当面对您表示同情真是太好了 纳什先生
How nice to have the opportunity to wish you commiserations in person, Mr Nash,
我猜今晚的《警务新闻报》
for I believe this evening's edition of the Illustrated Police News
已经印好了
will be leaving the printers
准备送到如饥似渴的读者手中
on its way to be devoured by its readership...
他们会发现天才纳什先生
Only later to discover that the genius, Mr Nash
做出了错误的指控
accused the wrong man.
没关系
It's no matter.
他们会在下一期向汉弗莱斯先生公开致歉
They will issue an apology to Mr Humphries in the next edition.
你会发现汉弗莱斯先生这样的人
Oh, I think you'll find that a man such as Mr Humphries
想要的可不是简单致歉
will want a little more than that.
应该是司法诉讼
A law suit, perhaps.
你这个女人
What a woman you are.
我现在更希望你能为我工作了
I'm afraid I'm even more eager to have you work for me than ever.
我的答案仍然是不
Well, my answer is still no.
我能做什么改变你的想法
Then what can I do to make you change your mind?
什么也做不了
Nothing.
总有点什么的
There's always something.
即便是你 斯嘉丽小姐 也有要价
Even you, Miss Scarlet, will have your price.
我想我可以试试勒索
I suppose I could try blackmail.
但我还是希望你自愿为我工作
However, perhaps I'd rather you come to me willingly..
而不是受强迫
Not coerced.
论手段我也可以跟你一样脏 先生
I can play as dirty as you, sir.
所以要相信我
So believe me when I say
你不会希望当我的敌人的
you do not want me as an enemy.
我希望当你的雇主
No, I want you as my employee.
考虑一下我的工作邀约吧
So take some time about my offer.
再见
Til then...
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet.
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.vip
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub
■
关注深影字幕组
微信公众号，更
多影视资讯，等
你来发现